In the fight for freedom everyone played a part.
Their Finest is a romance, war, drama film directed by Lone Scherfig.
During the Blitz of World War II, a female screenwriter works on a film celebrating
England's resilience as a way to buoy a weary populace's spirits.
Her efforts to dramatise the true story of two sisters who undertook their own maritime mission to
rescue wounded soldiers are met with mixed feelings by a dismissive all-male staff.
Catrin Cole, played by Gemma Arterton.
Tom Buckley, played by Sam Claflin.
Ambrose Hilliard / Uncle Frank, played by Bill Nighy.
Ellis Cole, played by Jack Huston.
Sophie Smith, played by Helen McCrory.
Sammy Smith, played by Eddie Marsan.
Their Finest is a 2016 British war comedy-drama film, directed by Lone Scherfig, written by Gaby
Chiappe, and based on the 2009 novel Their Finest Hour and a Half by Lissa Evans.
The film stars Gemma Arterton, Sam Claflin, Bill
Nighy, Jack Huston, Jake Lacy, Richard E.
Grant, Henry Goodman, Rachael Stirling, Eddie Marsan,
Amanda Root, Helen McCrory, and Claudia Jessie.
It tells the story of a British Ministry of Information film team making a morale-boosting film
about the Dunkirk evacuation during the Battle of Britain and the London Blitz.
Principal photography began in early September 2015 in London.
Their Finest was screened at the 2016 Toronto International Film Festival,
and was released in the UK on 21 April 2017 by Lionsgate.
The film is set during the time after Dunkirk, when the
Battle of Britain is turning into the Blitz.
The British government is desperately seeking to shore up the morale of the general population, and
is pursuing a long strategy of getting the US to join the war and defeat Hitler.
The Ministry of Information used artistic talent to pursue these ends.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, world war
ii, filmmaking, war propaganda, woman director.
The tone is emotional.